Lesson 35 Space odyssey
35 太空探索
First listen and then answer the following question.
听录音,然后回答以下问题.
When will it be possible for us to think seriously about colonising Mars?
什么时候人类才有可能认真地考虑征服火星?
hub: n.  （活动的）中心
The Moon is likely to become the industrial hub of the Solar System
月球很可能成为太阳系的工业中心,
supplying the rocket fuels for its ships,
为航天飞船提供燃料,
oxygen: n.  氧气
easily obtainable from the lunar rocks in the form of liquid oxygen.
这种燃料就是能够从月球岩石中很容易提炼出液态氧.
The reason lies in its gravity.
其原因在于月球的重力.
Because the Moon has only an eightieth of the Earth's mass,
因为月球的重量只有地球的1/80,
it requires 97% less energy
因此,只需消耗3%的能量,
to travel the quarter of a million miles from the Moon to Earth-orbit
就能飞跃25万英里从月球到达地球轨道,
than the 200 mile-journey from Earth's surface into orbit!
这是相对从地球表面进入地球轨道的200英里所耗能量来说的!
This may sound fantastic,but it is easily calculated.
这点听起来令人难以置信,但却很容易计算出来.
To escape from the Earth in a rocket,one must travel at seven miles per second.
要乘坐一枚火箭飞离地球,火箭的速度要达到每秒7英里,
The comparable speed from the Moon is only 1.5 miles per second.
而从月球出发的相应速度只是每秒1.5英里.
Because the gravity on the Moon's surface is only a sixth of Earth's
由于月球表面的重力仅是地球表面的1/6
Apollo: n.  阿波罗
(remember how easily the Apollo astronauts bounded along),
(还记得阿波罗飞船中的宇航员轻松地跳跃),
accelerate: v.  加速
it takes much less energy to accelerate to that 1.5mps than it does on Earth.
在月球上加速到每秒1.5英里比在地球上所用能源要少得多.
Moon dwellers will be able to fly in space
月球居民在太空遨游,
at only three per cent of the cost of similar journeys by their terrestrial cousins.
其费用仅是地球上朋友飞越同样路程所需费用的3%.
Arthur C.Clark once suggested a revolutionary idea passes through three phases:
亚瑟.C.克拉克曾提议,一种创新的想法要经过以下3个阶段:
1 'It's impossible--don't waste my time.'
1 "根本不可能,不要浪费我的时间."
2 'It's possible,but not worth doing.'
2 "可能,但不值得做."
3 'I said it was a good idea all along.'
3 "我一直说这是个好想法."
The idea of colonising Mars--a world 160 times more distant than the Moon--
征服火星的计划--一个比月球远160倍的星球--
will move decisively from the second phase to the third,
可以明确地从第2阶段进入第3阶段,
when a significant number of people are living permanently in space.
如果有相当数量的人永久性地住在太空的话.
fascination: n.  魅力
Mars has an extraordinary fascination for would-be voyagers.
火星对未来的星际旅客来说有着特殊的魅力.
America,Russia and Europe are filled with enthusiasts--
美国、俄罗斯和欧洲都有许多热心此项事业的人--
many of them serious and senior scientists- who dream of sending people to it.
他们中的不少人是认真和资深的科学家--他们一直梦想着把人送上火星.
Their aim is understandable.
他们的目标是可以理解的.
It is the one world in the Solar System that is most like the Earth.
火星是太阳系里与地球最相似的一颗行星.
It is a world of red sandy deserts (hence its name the Red Planet),
这是一个红色沙漠的世界(因而得名:红色行星),
chasm: n.  断层，裂口
cloudless skies,savage sandstorms,chasms wider than the Grand Canyon
无云的天空,凶猛的沙暴,比大峡谷还宽的裂缝,
and at least one mountain more than twice as tall as Everest.
起码有一座山有珠穆朗玛峰的近两倍高.
It seems ideal for settlement.
看起来,它很适合居住.